Hello friends in this video we'll talk
about quarter three results of IC
Lombard net premium income was up by
17.2% to
5,45 against
4300 and
five uh Market was expecting a revenue
of
5,572 uh net profit was up 67.9% so we
could see a huge jump in net profit
uh and has come to
724 against estimates of 635 and uh last
year profit of 432 so there has been a
clear beat when it comes to net profit
though in Revenue company has not been
able to beat the estimates solvency
ratio at
2.36% uh against
2.65% quarter on quarter so uh we can
say results have been good company has
been able to expand its margin
which is overall a very good positive
sign if we talk about its market cap
then it has a market cap of around
96,000 crores and a p of
43.3 uh Roe is of 17 and R is of
22.5 and has a dividend yield of 31 so
compared to other insurance companies
this particular stock is trading at a p
which is low than their P it is also
because it is a leader in
non Health uh Insurance segment it is in
fact a leader in this segment it does
vehicle and other insurance uh and uh
life insurance is uh health insurance is
something which uh uh uh Market gives
High premium to and that is the reason
why this is a stock which is having low
PE compared to its peers uh if we
compare this valuations against
historical then it is currently trading
at a historical average average is
around 45 and is trading at a price near
to that average only we could see there
is a tip after covid since insurance
claims have gone up there was an overall
stress in the economy and that has
raised number of insurance claim and
that has impacted company's
profitability but since then it has
picked up and is doing well now in fact
in current quarters as we have already
seen numbers have been pretty robust if
you compare its historical growth rate
then Last 5 Years sales C is 13% and
profit C here also is 133% so growth is
decent uh though not very high and as we
can see uh after covid there was a sharp
drop but uh then profitability have gone
up uh sales wise company has been very
consistent it has been able to improve
its sales year over year
uh at least from
2016 uh if we have a look at its
technicals then stock is currently
taking a trend andine support it did
take uh several times this support and
uh stock price have jumped uh it has an
all-time high of around
2300 Uh current trading price of around
1955 is near the support since results
are good we can expect it to go up um
there is a likely of it testing uh
levels of 2300 which is its alltime
high uh so these are few levels to watch
out for uh remember friends this
analysis is only for the educational
purpose kindly do your own due diligence
before investing in any stock thank you